<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://efi-robotics.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://efi-robotics.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-04-16T13:02:22+00:00</updated><id>https://efi-robotics.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Engineering For Intelligent Robotics</title><subtitle>Lab website. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">ARIA project awarded!</title><link href="https://efi-robotics.github.io/blog/2025/aria/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ARIA project awarded!"/><published>2025-02-20T12:11:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-20T12:11:00+00:00</updated><id>https://efi-robotics.github.io/blog/2025/aria</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://efi-robotics.github.io/blog/2025/aria/"><![CDATA[<p>📢 We’re very pleased to announce that our joint proposal with <a href="https://www.artimusrobotics.com/">Artimus Robotics</a> to ARIA for the <a href="https://www.aria.org.uk/opportunity-spaces/smarter-robot-bodies/robot-dexterity/">Robot Dexterity programme</a> has been awarded!</p> <p><a href="https://www.bristol.ac.uk/news/2025/february-/robot-dexterity-funding.html">Press release</a></p> <p>Stay tuned for updates.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="events"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[📢 We’re very pleased to announce that our joint proposal with Artimus Robotics to ARIA for the Robot Dexterity programme has been awarded! Press release Stay tuned for updates.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MultiTip project awarded!</title><link href="https://efi-robotics.github.io/blog/2024/multitip/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MultiTip project awarded!"/><published>2024-09-10T13:11:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-10T13:11:00+00:00</updated><id>https://efi-robotics.github.io/blog/2024/multitip</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://efi-robotics.github.io/blog/2024/multitip/"><![CDATA[<p>📢 We’re very pleased to announce that our proposal to Royal Society for an International Collaboration Award with South Korea has been awarded!</p> <p>Stay tuned for updates and job openings.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="events"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[📢 We’re very pleased to announce that our proposal to Royal Society for an International Collaboration Award with South Korea has been awarded! Stay tuned for updates and job openings.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Next concert announced</title><link href="https://efi-robotics.github.io/blog/2024/briso_autumn_2024/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Next concert announced"/><published>2024-09-09T13:11:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-09T13:11:00+00:00</updated><id>https://efi-robotics.github.io/blog/2024/briso_autumn_2024</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://efi-robotics.github.io/blog/2024/briso_autumn_2024/"><![CDATA[<p>📢 Our next concert’s booking page is up.</p> <p>📅 Saturday 23 November, 7:30pm</p> <p>📍 <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/84GpDtFRE1ebZWyr5">St George’s Bristol</a></p> <p>🎫 <a href="https://www.stgeorgesbristol.co.uk/whats-on/bristol-symphony-orchestra-3/"><strong>Book tickets</strong></a></p> <h2 id="programme">Programme</h2> <p><strong>Bruckner</strong> Overture in G minor</p> <p><strong>Wagner</strong> Tristan and Isolde: Prelude and Liebestod</p> <p><strong>Sibelius</strong> Symphony No 2 in D major Op 43</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/bso.flyer.digital.final-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/bso.flyer.digital.final-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/bso.flyer.digital.final-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/bso.flyer.digital.final.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="SMG" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="events"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[📢 Our next concert’s booking page is up. 📅 Saturday 23 November, 7:30pm 📍 St George’s Bristol 🎫 Book tickets Programme Bruckner Overture in G minor Wagner Tristan and Isolde: Prelude and Liebestod Sibelius Symphony No 2 in D major Op 43]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MANiBOT project started!</title><link href="https://efi-robotics.github.io/blog/2023/manibot/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MANiBOT project started!"/><published>2023-12-01T13:11:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-01T13:11:00+00:00</updated><id>https://efi-robotics.github.io/blog/2023/manibot</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://efi-robotics.github.io/blog/2023/manibot/"><![CDATA[<p>📢 The Horizon Europe <a href="https://manibot-project.eu/">MANiBOT project</a> has now started!</p> <p>MANiBOT aims to empower bi-manual, mobile, service robots with superior physical capabilities; able to perform a wide variety of manipulation tasks, with highly diverse objects, in a human-like manner and performance, in diverse, challenging environments.</p> <p>The project seeks to revolutionise the robotics landscape by enhancing robot’s handling skills, including simple grasping, pick-and-place operations, bi-manual and non-prehensile manipulation, and ensuring adaptive responses to changing environments or to the properties of objects.</p> <p>To achieve these capabilities, innovations will be developed in the fields of advanced environment understanding, efficient manipulation techniques, robot cognitive functions and physical intelligence. The researchers will implement their solutions with a focus on baggage handling and supermarket shelves’ restocking, with piloting of robots in relevant environments.</p> <p>Follow us on <a href="https://twitter.com/MANiBOT_project">X (Twitter)</a> and<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/showcase/manibot/">LinkedIn</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="events"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[📢 The Horizon Europe MANiBOT project has now started! MANiBOT aims to empower bi-manual, mobile, service robots with superior physical capabilities; able to perform a wide variety of manipulation tasks, with highly diverse objects, in a human-like manner and performance, in diverse, challenging environments. The project seeks to revolutionise the robotics landscape by enhancing robot’s handling skills, including simple grasping, pick-and-place operations, bi-manual and non-prehensile manipulation, and ensuring adaptive responses to changing environments or to the properties of objects. To achieve these capabilities, innovations will be developed in the fields of advanced environment understanding, efficient manipulation techniques, robot cognitive functions and physical intelligence. The researchers will implement their solutions with a focus on baggage handling and supermarket shelves’ restocking, with piloting of robots in relevant environments. Follow us on X (Twitter) andLinkedIn.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">PhD studentship on bimanual robotic manipulation</title><link href="https://efi-robotics.github.io/blog/2023/phd-manibot/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PhD studentship on bimanual robotic manipulation"/><published>2023-05-12T13:11:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-12T13:11:00+00:00</updated><id>https://efi-robotics.github.io/blog/2023/phd-manibot</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://efi-robotics.github.io/blog/2023/phd-manibot/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="project-information">Project information</h3> <p>We seek a talented and motivated new PhD student to join our team at the University of Bristol. The successful applicant will join the largest centre for multidisciplinary robotics research in the UK. This project will apply cutting-edge robotics and machine learning approaches to advance the physical intelligence of robots toward human-like bimanual object manipulation.</p> <p>The studentship will be based in Bristol Robotics Laboratory and the University of Bristol, co-supervised by <a href="https://lepora.com/">Prof. Nathan Lepora</a> and Dr Efi Psomopoulou.</p> <p>The role is part of a €7M Horizon Europe-funded project on pushing the limit of physical intelligence and performance of robots, particularly in bimanual manipulation. The student will have the benefit of being part of a large international collaboration of many leading European research groups in robotic manipulation, and a vibrant team of postdoctoral and PhD researchers in the <a href="https://www.bristolroboticslab.com/dexterous-robotics">Dexterous Robotics group</a>.</p> <p>The project introduces a novel technological framework for enabling robots to perform complex object manipulation tasks, allowing them to efficiently manipulate highly diverse objects with various properties in terms of shape, size and physical characteristics similarly to how humans do. We particularly focus on bimanual manipulation robots that can operate in challenging, real-world, possibly human-populated environments, and we further research, develop and fuse the necessary technologies in robot perception, cognition, mechatronics and control, to allow such, human-like, efficient robotic objects manipulation towards step changes in contemporary service robots.</p> <p>The position will be based at the <a href="https://www.bristolroboticslab.com/">Bristol Robotics Laboratory</a> the largest centre for multidisciplinary robotics research in the UK. It will operate within the internationally-leading Dexterous Robotics Group at Bristol Robotics Laboratory, which is an exciting and vibrant research group with several recent lecturer appointment, 25 researchers and a range of state-of-the-art robot equipment. You will use dedicated facilities and expertise from the Robotics Lab in addition to those of the Faculties of Engineering and Science at the University of Bristol and project partners.</p> <p>You will be working in a team with the two supervisors, a postdoctoral Research Associate and a Research Technician (both to be advertised soon). We are intending to recruit other PhD students to the team to provide a cohesive and supportive environment for the members.</p> <h3 id="candidate-requirements">Candidate requirements</h3> <p>We strongly encourage applications from STEM with experience in engineering / robotics (e.g., mathematics, control theory, robotics, computer science, mechatronics, or other related engineering discipline). You will need to demonstrate your ability in conducting research in a related field or a strong motivation in learning those skills.</p> <p>Applications are sought from high performing individuals who have, or are expected to obtain, at least a 2.1 degree (or equivalent). Possession of a relevant Master’s degree or research experience would be advantageous but is not required.</p> <p>We welcome applications from those with non-standard qualifications who can demonstrate knowledge, experience and skills developed in the workplace, or elsewhere, relevant to the programme of study.</p> <h3 id="start-date">Start date</h3> <p>The post starts on <strong>November 1st 2023</strong> and lasts for 3.5 years.</p> <h3 id="application-process">Application process</h3> <p>Please contact me (<strong>efi.psomopoulou[at]bristol.ac.uk</strong>) and Professor Nathan Lepora (<strong>n.lepora[at]bristol.ac.uk</strong>) for more details about this post and to apply. Applicants should send a short CV (2 pages max) and 1-page personal statement describing why they are interested in the post.</p> <p>Personal statement: Please also provide a personal statement that describes your training and experience so far, your motivation for doing a PhD, your motivations for applying to the University of Bristol, and why you think we should select you. We are keen to support applicants from minority and under-represented backgrounds (based on protected characteristics) and those who have experienced other challenges or disadvantages. We encourage you to use your personal statement to ensure we can take these factors into account.</p> <p>We will keep applications open until the post is filled.</p> <h3 id="funding-information">Funding information</h3> <p>This is a fully-funded PhD studentship at standard UKRI rates (currently £18,022 for 2023/24 year). Home fees for UK and Irish residents will be covered. There will be additional funds from the project grant for equipment and travel that are substantially in excess of those usually available for PhD studies.</p> <p><strong>NOTE:</strong> This scholarship covers tuition fees for UK and Irish citizens and EU applicants who have been resident in the UK for at least 3 years (some constraints are in place around residence for education) and have UK settlement or pre-settlement status under the EU Settlement Scheme. International students can apply but would need to cover the difference between home and overseas fees.</p>]]></content><author><name>Efi Psomopoulou</name></author><category term="grasping"/><category term="manipulation"/><category term="physical-human-robot-interaction"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Project information We seek a talented and motivated new PhD student to join our team at the University of Bristol. The successful applicant will join the largest centre for multidisciplinary robotics research in the UK. This project will apply cutting-edge robotics and machine learning approaches to advance the physical intelligence of robots toward human-like bimanual object manipulation. The studentship will be based in Bristol Robotics Laboratory and the University of Bristol, co-supervised by Prof. Nathan Lepora and Dr Efi Psomopoulou. The role is part of a €7M Horizon Europe-funded project on pushing the limit of physical intelligence and performance of robots, particularly in bimanual manipulation. The student will have the benefit of being part of a large international collaboration of many leading European research groups in robotic manipulation, and a vibrant team of postdoctoral and PhD researchers in the Dexterous Robotics group. The project introduces a novel technological framework for enabling robots to perform complex object manipulation tasks, allowing them to efficiently manipulate highly diverse objects with various properties in terms of shape, size and physical characteristics similarly to how humans do. We particularly focus on bimanual manipulation robots that can operate in challenging, real-world, possibly human-populated environments, and we further research, develop and fuse the necessary technologies in robot perception, cognition, mechatronics and control, to allow such, human-like, efficient robotic objects manipulation towards step changes in contemporary service robots. The position will be based at the Bristol Robotics Laboratory the largest centre for multidisciplinary robotics research in the UK. It will operate within the internationally-leading Dexterous Robotics Group at Bristol Robotics Laboratory, which is an exciting and vibrant research group with several recent lecturer appointment, 25 researchers and a range of state-of-the-art robot equipment. You will use dedicated facilities and expertise from the Robotics Lab in addition to those of the Faculties of Engineering and Science at the University of Bristol and project partners. You will be working in a team with the two supervisors, a postdoctoral Research Associate and a Research Technician (both to be advertised soon). We are intending to recruit other PhD students to the team to provide a cohesive and supportive environment for the members. Candidate requirements We strongly encourage applications from STEM with experience in engineering / robotics (e.g., mathematics, control theory, robotics, computer science, mechatronics, or other related engineering discipline). You will need to demonstrate your ability in conducting research in a related field or a strong motivation in learning those skills. Applications are sought from high performing individuals who have, or are expected to obtain, at least a 2.1 degree (or equivalent). Possession of a relevant Master’s degree or research experience would be advantageous but is not required. We welcome applications from those with non-standard qualifications who can demonstrate knowledge, experience and skills developed in the workplace, or elsewhere, relevant to the programme of study. Start date The post starts on November 1st 2023 and lasts for 3.5 years. Application process Please contact me (efi.psomopoulou[at]bristol.ac.uk) and Professor Nathan Lepora (n.lepora[at]bristol.ac.uk) for more details about this post and to apply. Applicants should send a short CV (2 pages max) and 1-page personal statement describing why they are interested in the post. Personal statement: Please also provide a personal statement that describes your training and experience so far, your motivation for doing a PhD, your motivations for applying to the University of Bristol, and why you think we should select you. We are keen to support applicants from minority and under-represented backgrounds (based on protected characteristics) and those who have experienced other challenges or disadvantages. We encourage you to use your personal statement to ensure we can take these factors into account. We will keep applications open until the post is filled. Funding information This is a fully-funded PhD studentship at standard UKRI rates (currently £18,022 for 2023/24 year). Home fees for UK and Irish residents will be covered. There will be additional funds from the project grant for equipment and travel that are substantially in excess of those usually available for PhD studies. NOTE: This scholarship covers tuition fees for UK and Irish citizens and EU applicants who have been resident in the UK for at least 3 years (some constraints are in place around residence for education) and have UK settlement or pre-settlement status under the EU Settlement Scheme. International students can apply but would need to cover the difference between home and overseas fees.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UK-RAS Showcase</title><link href="https://efi-robotics.github.io/blog/2023/ukras-showcase/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UK-RAS Showcase"/><published>2023-03-15T13:11:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-15T13:11:00+00:00</updated><id>https://efi-robotics.github.io/blog/2023/ukras-showcase</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://efi-robotics.github.io/blog/2023/ukras-showcase/"><![CDATA[<p>📢 Registration is now open for <a href="https://www.ukras.org.uk/robotics-summer-showcase/">The International Robotics Showcase 2023</a>!</p> <p>This free event, co-organised by the <a href="https://www.ukras.org.uk/about/early-career-forum/">UK-RAS Early Career Forum</a>, seeks to bring together members of the UK-RAS Network, industry, academia, government, policy, public and funding bodies as part of an exciting variety of activities aimed at exploring what the future of Robotics and Autonomous Systems holds for the community and beyond!</p> <p><a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/international-robotics-showcase-2023-tickets-569653869057">Registrations</a></p> <p><a href="https://www.ukras.org.uk/robotics-summer-showcase/call-for-exhibitors-and-demos/">Call for Exhibitors and Demos</a></p> <p><a href="https://www.ukras.org.uk/robotics-summer-showcase/call-for-posters/">Call for posters</a> 📅 deadline: 31 May 2023, by 12 noon (BST)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="events"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[📢 Registration is now open for The International Robotics Showcase 2023! This free event, co-organised by the UK-RAS Early Career Forum, seeks to bring together members of the UK-RAS Network, industry, academia, government, policy, public and funding bodies as part of an exciting variety of activities aimed at exploring what the future of Robotics and Autonomous Systems holds for the community and beyond! Registrations Call for Exhibitors and Demos Call for posters 📅 deadline: 31 May 2023, by 12 noon (BST)]]></summary></entry></feed>